There has been credible reporting over
the years that the that the Israelis may
have had something to do with the
Kennedy assassination, may have had
advanced warning about the Kennedy
assassination, and that and that they
either participated in it or allowed it
to happen or didn't warn the United
States that it was going to happen
because Kennedy not just refused to give
them nuclear technology, he actively
stood in the way of them acquiring
nuclear technology to create a bomb.
>> Ben Green resigned over it.
>> That's right.
>> The subject of Kennedy, his
assassination, and his opposition to CIA
regime change operations, and the Israel
lobby has been subject to lots of debate
among Americans, especially dissidents,
for over 60 years. But what's the truth
about it? Did Kennedy's opposition to
the Israel lobby in terms of acquiring
nuclear weapons or forcing AZC or trying
to register under the FARA Act as a
foreign lobby contribute to his death in
any way? That's a subject that John
Kiriakou and Tucker Carlson discuss
here. I've seen this interview before,
but my mind keeps coming back to it and
some of the dynamics that they discuss
and whether they're pertinent to the
modern times. So let's take a look.
Please like the video, subscribe to the
channel, hype the video if you can, and
let's get going.
>> So if you think that um by the way, I
just want to be clear, I'm not blaming
the Israelis for any of this. It was US
government officials who decided to sell
out their country.
>> That's right.
>> Um
because I don't know. Who knows why
exactly. But anyway, the way they did.
Um
how do you disengage?
How do you get American sovereignty
back? How do you break the stranglehold
of the Israeli lobby on
the US government?
>> You know, just like I do, that it it
wasn't always like this.
The
the AIPAC, the American Israel Public
Affairs Committee, only became a a major
player in American politics
beginning around 1970
when President Nixon formally changed US
policy toward Israel to guarantee the
safety and security of Israel. That
changed things.
What he should have done at the same
time was to force AIPAC to register as a
as a foreign agent, right? I mean, it
clearly represents the foreign policy
>> John F. Kennedy tried to do that.
>> John F. Kennedy did try to do that.
>> Yeah, it didn't work well for him.
>> And and I think President Johnson was
afraid to take them on.
And he never did anything.
>> He was working with them. He worked
closely. He covered up the USS Liberty.
>> Liberty.
>> The Israelis take the blame for that.
They're the ones who committed the
murders.
But it I don't think Lyndon Johnson gets
the credit he deserves.
>> Absolutely not. I agree with you.
>> the surviving crew
of that ship for talking about it.
>> Yes. You know, I went back to the
original press reporting. I I wanted to
do an episode of my own podcast on the
Liberty just because so many people
still talk about it. We're talking about
19 what? 67?
So, I went back to the original
reporting and the the press
releases coming out of the State
Department and the Defense Department
were blistering.
And then the president said, "What are
you doing?
Stop criticizing Israel."
>> Well, they yeah.
What do you think that was?
>> Yeah, that was the Israel lobby.
>> Yeah, that's exactly what the Israel
lobby did and I would push back on
Kyriacou just a little bit. The United
States got deeply entrenched in this
entangling alliance with Israel before
Nixon, though that does ring true as far
as the '73 war. Golda Meir did hold the
president essentially ransom to come out
and bail out the Israel lobby spurring
on the biggest transfer of military
equipment across the globe that had ever
happened at that point. Obviously,
during the Yom Kippur War, but also in
the '67 war, the United States poured
tons of money into that, too. We're
already attached at the hip to Israel
and decided to defend its borders
thousands of miles away when those Arab
countries didn't stand to threaten the
United States whatsoever. So, I think it
goes beyond that. But, yeah, the USS
Liberty was a total act of criminality,
and you did see initial backlash from
the president, from the State
Department, but then the president put
the kibosh on it. LBJ put the kibosh on
it just as he did a failure to seek
Kennedy's proposals through to stop
Ben-Gurion at the time in the '60s from
acquiring nuclear weapons from the
United States in the Dimona project.
They literally stole it from the United
States. We're not supposed to ask
questions about that. And also getting
the the precursor organization to AIPAC
was called the American Zionist Council
to register under FARA. LBJ was tepid
and feckless when it came to the Israel
lobby. Kennedy was courageous and heroic
when it came to confronting the Israel
lobby. And look which one of those died,
and look which one of those lived.
>> But, why would Lyndon Johnson have been
such a slave?
>> I think he was afraid.
>> What do you think the root of his fear
was? What was he afraid of?
>> You know, I There has been credible
reporting over the years that the that
the Israelis may have had something to
do with the Kennedy assassination, may
have had advanced warning about the
Kennedy assassination,
and that and that they either
participated in it or allowed it to
happen or didn't warn the United States
that it was going to happen because
Kennedy not just refused to give them
nuclear technology, he actively stood in
the way of them acquiring nuclear
technology to create a bomb.
>> resigned over it.
>> That's right.
>> He he was demanding inspections of the
Dimona facility, the nuclear facility in
Israel.
>> That's right.
>> Um yeah, I don't know the answer. I can
promise you everyone around the world
thinks that's true.
>> Yeah.
>> You don't go to a country where people
don't think that's true. Um, but
>> Yeah, that's exactly true. And if you
doubt what we're saying, not only about
Kennedy trying to get there to be
inspections in Dimona to prevent the
transfer of the United States nuclear
secrets to Israel, you can take a look
at an archive which also discusses his
attempt to force the AZC, the precursor
to AIPAC, to register under FARA in
let me see, I'm going to share my screen
here
in a video in in this website right
here, the Israel Lobby Archive. It's at
israellobby.org.
It doesn't translate super well to
sharing, but this website talks about
the fact that Kennedy did this with a
documented record of all the official
transcripts and federal documents
pertaining to it, including the November
21st, 1962
order to the AZC to register under FARA.
Again, it's kind of hard to present in
this window, but here's the document you
can see with the Kennedy administration
and and namely the Assistant Attorney
General Walter Yeagley at the time
sending a notice to the AZC to register
under FARA to comply with federal
legislation that made all foreign
lobbies have to register as such. And
that law is still in place. That's what
all the foreign lobbies register under
except for the Israel Lobby, except for
AIPAC. They get a special carve out,
just as they do the special carve out to
develop nuclear weapons, not just in
violation of the NPT,
but in violation of basic tenets of
friendship or what would be friendship
between two typical allies. And that
that that be that you don't steal our
technology, which Israel exactly did,
and that is why this has been discussed
so much throughout time and why we may
never get answers.
>> I
I don't know if it is true. Um but it's
just interesting that Lyndon Johnson was
such a slave
that he attacked Americans for talking
about the murder of Americans by a
foreign power.
>> Mhm.
>> That's like
>> And there was the Israelis clearly knew
that it was an American ship. It was
flying the American flag and it said USS
Liberty on the side of it.
>> Yeah. And then they waited something
like 45 minutes after attacking it, and
then they came back and attacked it
again.
So, there's no question they tried to
sink it.
>> Yeah.
>> Exactly.
>> And they they said, "Oh, no. We thought
it was from the Egyptian navy."
Like, come on, you guys.
>> Yeah, I mean, it's a total farce.
There's still a lot of lingering
questions about that and survivors from
the USS Liberty will still tell the
truth, no matter how controversial it
is, in comparison to the farcical
government narrative on it, like Phil
Tourney, who's been on several shows,
including Candace Owens, and admired the
fact that Candace wanted his story to be
told so much that he gave Candace Owens
his own Purple Heart in thanks for that.
That's what we're dealing with here, a
vast criminal underbelly in terms of the
American state, the American
intelligence apparatus, and the
corporate media in in collusion to hide
the truth, to conceal it from the
public, especially as it pertains to
things that would not only be
embarrassing, but downright criminal
when it comes to America's greatest ally
abroad, the real albatross around the
neck, if you listen to John Mearsheimer,
and this podcast subscribing to the
Mearsheimer view on things.
>> Come on, you can come up with something
better than that. So, how do you
disentangle at this point? So, my
impression is, just as an observer of
government, that the Israeli government
is like embedded within the US
government at this point.
>> It seems that way to me. Yes.
>> So, it's probably not a simple thing
>> No, I think it's
>> to undo that.
>> Very, very difficult. Yeah. I think that
AIPAC really does have to register as a
as a foreign agent. It really does.
Listen, if I had to register as a
foreign agent because the the Abu Dhabi
of Chamber of Commerce hired me to write
four op-eds and I had to go to fara.gov
and register, then AIPAC should be
registered.
>> So, but if the United States were ever
to take a
more,
you know, arms-length posture toward
Israel,
what do you think the consequences would
be?
>> I honestly don't think there would be
any consequences.
Israel is a is an important and valuable
ally.
>> Mhm.
>> So are a lot of other countries.
>> Yep.
>> And I just don't think the Israelis
should be treated any differently than
than the Brits or the French or the
Greeks or, you know, anybody else.
>> Imagine that though and imagine how
radical of a viewpoint that is. We know
that Israel gets special carve-outs for
its foreign policy, the biggest foreign
aid recipient in the United States, $4
billion a year. People say, "Obama shut
the door on the Israel lobby by creating
the JCPOA." And I guess he did. I think
I would applaud that measure, but in the
same act, he upped the financial aid to
Israel to $4 billion. I think it's
technically $3.8 billion per year, which
is expanded mercilessly while we're $40
trillion in debt since October 7th.
Since then, they've received something
like $35
tr- $35 billion from the United States.
While Americans are being bled dry,
while inflation destroys lives and debt
plunges us into shackles going into the
future. That is what's happening here
and yeah, AIPAC has to register under
FARA and it's not easy to rein this in
at this point. The toothpaste is out of
the tube. The Israel lobby's control
over our government is palpable. Not
only Congress, but the presidency, the
deep state. Miriam Adelson seems to have
more power over US foreign policy than
the administration. But of course, she's
tied to the administration.
That's what we're dealing with here. But
the good thing in our favor is that the
American culture is moving away from
this Israel first doctrine that mostly
only older people hold at this point.
The Fox News viewership generally
speaking have that viewpoint. This
breaks down on demographic lines and I
don't think they're going to be able to
maintain this stranglehold on power
quite the same in years to come. Now,
we'll have to see that play out for a
while, but that's a true dynamic, I
think.
>> Why do they get special treatment? I
just don't understand that.
>> than that. We sacrifice all of our other
relationships on their behalf.
>> right. Yes.
>> Right.
>> So, their priorities become our
priorities and all of a sudden they're
our only friend. And you can't tell me
that's accidental.
>> That's right.
>> They're literally our only friend and
they're not a they're not a friend.
>> They have a much longer-term view of
these things than we do. They They began
to try to implement this policy in the
in the '60s
and it finally came to fruition. It's
prime minister after prime minister
after prime minister cultivates not just
American political figures, but but
wealthy American Jews and says, "Look,
you know, we've got a lot of lobbying to
do. We've got a lot of PR to do. We're
going to need money to do this."
And money's never been a problem.
>> Yeah, that's exactly what it is. It's so
much money from this lobby and from
Netanyahu's cutouts in the United States
that do this bidding on behalf of that
country and at the peril to our own. The
peril to US citizens again languishing
in debt and inflation and domestic
crises that come under a
We come under attack over free speech
codes and free speech laws if we dare
criticize Israel. There's no laws in
place in the American states that
prevent us from criticizing other
American states, but there is several
dozen states with laws that either
criminalize or make penalty of Americans
criticizing Israel. Just think about
that. There are modern ways in which
Americans boycott other American states
for having bad, you know, in their eyes
gun policies or abortion policies or all
sorts of other policies on the basis
that it's a terrible state. But if you
do that to Israel, you come under the
crosshairs of a regime that wants to
favor that country above ours. It's
outright criminal. It's absurd and
Americans are starting to take notice.
It isn't panning out in terms of
affecting the political climate yet,
especially on a federal level, but I
dare say I think it will. I think there
will be a time when in the presidential
debates the subject isn't who agrees
with and supports Israel more. It's
actually who
denies and deprives Israel of funding
more. That's what it's going to be. It's
not going to be the same political
monster that we've dealt with our entire
lives, and I don't think the shift is
going to be an easy one, but the
information stranglehold is over. The
corporate media and just the lackeys of
the regime in the media realm have lost
their persuasive pull among the
populace. It's mostly due to the rise of
independent media, the ability for shows
like this to speak the truth, to get to
the root of these stories that the
federal government and their lackeys in
the corporate media have been concealing
for years, and I think that's what we're
dealing with here. As far as JFK and his
assassination, well, the JFK files
revealed some interesting things that is
not often talked about again in the
corporate media about the CIA and its
decision to target Kennedy in so many
ways. You had Dulles, Alan Dulles, the
man that Kennedy dismissed as the head
of the CIA heading up the Warren
Commission to investigate his death,
probably the biggest absurd conflict of
interest in human history. You had James
Angleton, a CIA officer with immense
power to cultivate the relationship
between the CIA and Mossad, Israel's
counterpart of the CIA, and gave him
extensive powers reporting directly to
the director of the CIA and despising
Kennedy the entire time. You had the
story of Garrett Underhill, a man who
worked at the CIA, announced that there
was a mass conspiracy within the CIA to
kill Kennedy, not maybe not a mass
conspiracy, but he said that there was a
conspiracy to kill Kennedy, and that is
what had been done. He was going to be
interviewed by investigators of the
assassination, and just before they were
able to contact him and set up an
appointment to discuss this assertion,
he was found dead in a mysterious
suicide in which a gun was found under
his left hand, but he was right-handed.
That's what you get with this story, and
I think the questions will linger on
forever. To what extent did either the
CIA or Israel play a role in Kennedy's
assassination? I guess that's for you,
the viewer, to decide, but I think that
it was much more than the American
people are led to believe, and I think
basically all dissidents essentially
agree with that at this point, and it
becomes more and more clear the more
information comes out, the more that the
CIA was revealed to have tracked Oswald
for a long time, and those records come
out. But that's that's what we are
dealing with here. What did you think
about Tucker and Kiriakou's position
here? What is the way to rein the Israel
lobby in?
And who killed Kennedy? What what's the
truth about that? Let me know in the
comments down below. Like the video,
subscribe to the channel, hype the video
if you can, and check out Tucker's site,
um his channel. Subscribe to him, great
segment with a great guest. I could
listen to Kiriakou for hours. He's
fantastic. And if you like this video on
Breakdown, please subscribe as a YouTube
member. You can do that by clicking the
join button down below. That makes you a
member of Liberty Vault, and I really
appreciate you being a member. And if
you want a free copy of my first book,
Compact of the Republic, click the link
in the description down below. That
sends you to a website, just plug in
your email right there, and I'll send
you a full free copy of that book, no
obligations whatsoever. And look, I have
a few demands from this sinister Israel
first corrupt regime, and I won't
apologize for them. No more war, no more
debt, no more inflation, and no more
empire.
Peace out, guys. Catch in the next one.